Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep, brother Tanzil.
And God spake all these words, saying,
"I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything
that is in heaven above, or that is in
the earth beneath, or that is in the
water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
holy.
Six days shalt thou labor, and do all
thy work. But the seventh day is the
sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work. Thou, nor thy
son,
nor thy daughter, thy manservant, nor
thy maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbors. We read Exodus 21 through
17 and may the Lord have a blessing to
the reading of his word. In Jesus' name
we pray.
Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of
here to debate, we're here to spread the
true gospel of Jesus. So please be as
direct as possible with your questions
so we can be as direct as possible with
our answers out of the King James Bible.
No other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also keep
in mind this is a live stream so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. Let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We've got brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Julius. Good evening everybody.
Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Tanzael.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
And we have sister Casey with us as well
as a guest caller and I'm brother
Cornell. Sister
Deborah, what is our first question of
the evening?
Uh yes, there are several holdover
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Um Linda Stringer says, "Since Enoch is
considered
pseudepigraphical
writing,
scholars dispute 1 Timothy, 2 Timothy,
Ephesians,
Colossians, and Thessalonians are
pseudepigraphical,
also. Paul is not believed to be the
author. Thoughts.
All right. So, brother Julius is asking
you about this question here if you
could give us a little explanation on
that. Pseudo
depict raffle
and take it from there, brother.
Uh yes, thank you for the question.
Uh the Apocrypha itself with all those
lost books are pseudepigraphal,
uh which means that they are not
uh
biblically accepted nor biblically
written, but attributed to the writers,
which is false.
Now, Paul wrote Well, let's go to 2
Peter 1:10 there.
Let's get right to the bottom of this. 2
Peter, the first chapter.
Because this is what people do. They
want to accept the Apocrypha and the
lost books and the book of Enoch.
It's not biblical. None of it is
biblical, cuz sisters and brothers,
there's too many contradictions in it.
2 Peter 1 and read verse 16.
For we have not followed cunningly
devised fable. That's what
That is what the Apocrypha are. That's
what the book of Enoch is. Cunningly
devised fables. Go ahead.
When we made known unto you the power
and coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, but
were eyewitnesses of his majesty. Get
down to verse 21 and go ahead.
For the prophecy came not in old time by
the will of man. But holy men of God
spake as they were moved by the Holy
Ghost. So, these men that wrote the
Bible from Genesis to Revelation uh are
holy men and scribes. Okay? So, now,
Paul wrote the epistles, the ones that
he
Well, the ones that he wrote, he tell
you he wrote it his own hand. The ones
that they still letters for him, but
Paul had a hard He also had a hard
scribe.
Let me show you what I'm talking about.
Let's go to
uh Philemon.
Philemon is only one uh chapter, Tenzel.
Philemon, the first chapter.
We're going to read two verses.
Let me know when you get it. Philemon 1
It's right after after the book of
Titus.
Okay.
Uh yeah.
It's right before Hebrews. Right before
Hebrews.
Yeah, that's one of them books that get
passed over quite a lot. Yeah, you'll
pass it real quick.
All right.
Read verse 1, Philemon 1
and 1. When you get it, brother, read
it. Paul, a prisoner of Jesus Christ and
Timothy our brother unto Philemon our
beloved beloved dearly beloved and
fellow laborer. Now, look what Paul said
in verse 19.
I Paul have written
I Paul have written it with my own hand.
Uh-huh.
I will pay it.
Albeit, I do not say to thee how thou
owest unto me even thy own self besides.
So, Paul tell you I'm writing to you
with my own hand.
That's why the book said holy men wrote
as they were moved by the Holy Spirit.
Paul wrote this with his own hand. Let's
go to Romans 1.
Romans chapter 1
and read verse 1, Tenzel.
Paul, a servant of Jesus Christ, called
to be an apostle, separated unto the
gospel of God. Now, Paul wrote this
uh to the Romans. Skip down to verse 7
and 8. You can go ahead.
To all that be in Rome, beloved of God,
called to be saints. Grace to you and
peace from God our Father and the Lord
Jesus Christ.
But first I
That's good, brother. That's That's
verse 8, right?
That's verse 7. Continue to read.
First, I thank my God through Jesus
Christ for you all, that your faith is
spoken of throughout the whole world.
Now, fast forward to Romans the 16th
chapter, and I got one verse there.
Because remember,
Paul had a medical problem. He had a
personal affliction.
And so, Paul most likely had a problem
with his eyes.
That's why some of the epistles that he
wrote Look at how Look at all of Paul's
writings, and look how they start.
Paul to the such and such. Paul to the
such and such and such.
Now, Romans the 16th chapter, the ones
that he wasn't able to write, he had a
scribe.
Read.
Picking up at verse 20.
And the God of peace shall bruise Satan
under your feet shortly. The grace of
our Lord Jesus Christ be with you. Amen.
Uh-huh.
Timotheus, my workfellow, and Lucius,
and Jason,
and and Sosipater
>> Sosipater. Sosipater.
my kinsmen, salute you. Uh-huh.
Tertius, who wrote I
>> I Tertius.
I Tertius, who wrote this epistle,
salute you in the Lord. Tertius was
Paul's scribe.
Because Paul had some vision problems.
So, the ones that he did write, he told
you I wrote it with my own hand. But the
ones that he didn't write, he had a
scribe. So, that's why these books that
Paul written are not pseudo uh
epigraphal.
They are
a pistol letters and mold you told you
in Saint John the five chapter Jesus
told you about Moses had you believe
Moses you would have believed me because
Moses wrote about me the Lord told Moses
what to write the
the angel speak to me he wrote it
so therefore that's the answer to that
all the other stuff that's not biblical
that's attributed to the authors are not
authentic.
That's why you can't find no writers of
them but you can find the writers of the
Bible.
That's all I got Cornell.
All right.
Thank you for that brother hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one.
Next one Patricia Henderson asked for
you to explain Jude nine.
All right.
Patricia would like some light shed
brother Jerome on that Jude nine which
is that book right before Revelation.
Let's go read it
brother Tenzel go to that Jude nine it's
just one book so go to the ninth verse.
One chapter.
When you get go ahead and read.
Yet Michael the Archangel when
contending with the devil
he disputed about the body of Moses
durst not bring against him a railing
accusation but said that the Lord rebuke
thee.
Yeah it pretty much it's
self-explanatory it mean what it say you
know Satan was disputing about
the body of Moses Archangel Michael
didn't bring no railing accusation
against Satan he just simply said to
Satan the Lord rebuke thee.
That's it.
That's all I got on it.
All right hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Our next one, more more more muddy
waters says, I have a question about
Proverbs 31:4-8.
Is it bad to drink alcohol?
All right, Andrea, in that Proverbs
31:4-8,
is it bad to drink alcohol?
Let's go read that. Proverbs 31.
Read it when you get there, Tenzel. 4-8.
It is not for kings, O Lemuel.
It is not for kings to drink wine, nor
for a prince is strong drink.
Lest they drink and forget the law,
and pervert the judgment of any of the
afflicted.
Give strong drink unto him that is ready
to perish,
and wine unto those that be of heavy
hearts. Let him drink and forget his
poverty, and remember his misery no
more.
Go ahead. That's it? Verse 8?
Open thy mouth.
Read verse 8. Yeah.
Open thy mouth for the dumb, in the
cause of all such as are appointed to
destruction. Okay. So,
if you if you got a problem if if if um
strong drink or wine
is problematic for you,
yeah, if it causes you to forget the law
and to pervert judgment,
then it can be a problem, most
definitely.
But, there's some other things. Right
after that, he says, give strong drink
to him that is ready to perish, and wine
to those that be of heavy heart. But,
let's look at something else. Let's go
to 1 Timothy, the fifth chapter, and we
going to read one verse there. 1 Timothy
5 and 23.
Read that when you get there, brother.
Drink no longer water, but use a little
wine for thy stomach's sake and thine
often infirmities. Yeah, little wine for
thy stomach's sake. Nothing wrong with
that. It's when you trying to master it
and it causes you to pervert judgment is
when it's problematic. Like it says in
Proverbs 20 and 1, wine is a mocker and
strong drink is raging and whosoever is
deceived thereby is not wise. But let's
look let's look at what they called
Jesus. Let's go to Matthew 11 and 19.
Matthew 11 and 19.
Read that when you get there, brother.
The Son of man came eating and drinking
and they say, "Behold, a man gluttonous
and a winebibber,
a friend of publicans and sinners.
But wisdom is justified of her
children." That's right. So, whatever
they called Jesus drink Jesus had to
drink some wine and it wasn't a problem
for him,
but if it's a problem for you, like it
can be for some others because one
is not enough. I mean,
one is too many and a thousand is not
enough.
So, yes, it's a problem if you got that
mindset. Now, let's go to Deuteronomy 14
and 26 and this will be it.
Deuteronomy 14, read verse 26.
And thou shalt bestow that money for
whatsoever thy soul lusteth after, for
oxen
or for sheep or for wine or for strong
drink
or for whatsoever thy soul desire.
And thou shall eat there before the Lord
thy God and thou shall rejoice, thou and
thy household.
That's right. So, you rejoicing. You
might have a little wine and a little
strong drink. But, like uh brother Bouie
always says, look here.
Don't get drunk here cuz if you do, I
don't know you.
Mhm. So, the thing is
in moderation not that's wine is not
wrong. And if you in your house, you
drink like you want to and and go ahead
and get you some rest.
That's all I got.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. That's the
exercise knowing their limit. All right,
we're going to move on to our next
question.
Uh more more
more [clears throat] muddy waters also
asked, which was given an answer already
before, but the question is in Genesis
32 verse 28,
was Israel ever really a place? Was it
actually Jacob's name after God blessed
him? When it refers to the land of
Israel, is it really referring to a
small part in Jerusalem, Jacob's owns?
All right, brother Jerome, share some
light.
Well, it's it's about three questions
there, okay? So, I'm going to split them
up in answering them, okay? Um Again.
Was was Israel really a place? And
definitely, Israel uh is a place.
Um the children of Israel got a twin
brother called
uh he he's Esau, the Edomite.
They've been fighting against the
Palestinians who are the Arabs. They've
been fighting over there over this place
for centuries. Okay? So, yeah, it's a
literal place, okay? But, let's go to
the uh verse that you gave in the
question. Let's go to that Genesis
32.
Cuz that's talking about when uh
the angel wrestled with Jacob.
Genesis 32 verse 28.
And he said, "Thy name shall be called
no more Jacob, but Israel.
For as a prince has thou power with God
and with men, and has prevailed."
Okay. So,
Jacob was actually given
um, one of God's names. He was cuz God
got several names, you know?
Um, but yeah, Israel is one of God's
names. And and when he adopted Jacob, he
changed his name from Jacob to Israel,
okay? So, let's go to
uh Isaiah 43.
We're going to read verse 3 through 4,
and then we're going to skip.
Isaiah 43
verse 3 through 4.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
For I am the Lord thy God, the holy one
of Israel, thy savior.
I gave Egypt for thy ransom, Ethiopia
and Seba for thee.
And since thou was precious in my sight,
thou has been honorable.
And I have loved thee. Therefore, will I
give men for thee,
and people for thy life. Skip down to
verse 7.
Even everyone that is called by my name.
For I have created him for my glory. I
have formed him. Yeah, I have made him.
Mhm.
So, yeah.
Uh he told you
them people are
I made for myself and I named them I
gave them my name, which is Israel,
okay? So, now I want to um this third
question it says
when it refers to the land of Israel, is
it really referred to it as a small part
of Jerusalem Jacob owned?
No, that land Israel
ain't a small part uh uh uh
called Jerusalem that was given to Jacob
and he owned it. No, no. The children of
Israel were given the land of the
Canaanites,
okay? And the Lord told them, "I'm
giving it to you." And they them
Israelites
took
the Canaanites' land and then
they became their inheritance their
their inheritance and you know it became
known as the land
of Israel after that, okay? So, let's go
to Psalms 30
Numbers, I'm sorry. Numbers 34.
We're going to read verse 1 and 2 and
skip.
Numbers
Read verse 1 and 2.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
Command the children of Israel and say
unto them, When you come into the land
of Canaan, this is the land that shall
fall unto you for an inheritance,
even the land of Canaan with the coast
thereof.
Mhm. Skip and read verse 16 and 17.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
These are the names of the men which
shall divide the land unto you, Eleazar
the priest and Joshua the son of Nun.
Mhm.
So, he's going to divide that land among
the 12 tribes of Israel and Jerusalem is
just one city that actually became the
inheritance of the tribe of Judah
and Benjamin. But you got all the other
sons of Jacob, the other 11 tribes, and
they got an inheritance that that spans
all the way from
Syria
down to the Nile River.
You know. Yeah, but Jerusalem is just
one city that's that's divided as an
inheritance to
the
the tribe of Judah
and the tribe of Benjamin.
That's all I got on it.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one, Serinda Serena Kendall asked
for you to explain Exodus 4:24.
Who did the Lord want to kill? And also
Exodus 4:25
and 26.
Why did Zipporah do and say that?
All right. So, um
Brother Julius, can you share some light
on that question? Absolutely. Let's go
to Let's read the Exodus 4:10. We going
to pick this up at verse 20. We going We
going to get us a name.
This who This who the scripture was
talking about. Go ahead.
And Moses took his wife and his son and
set them upon an ass. And they returned
to the land of Egypt, and Moses took the
rod of God in his hand. Skip down to
verse 22.
And thou shalt say unto Pharaoh, "Thus
saith the Lord, Israel is my son,
even my firstborn. Uh-huh.
And I say And I say unto thee, "Let my
son go that he may serve me. If thou
refuse to let him go? Behold, I will
slay thee, thy son, even thy firstborn.
So, the Lord said Moses down the spring
Israel out of Egypt. Moses is dealing
with Pharaoh and all these plagues and
everything.
But, time went by and go ahead and verse
24.
And it came to pass by the way at the
end that the Lord met him and sought to
kill him.
This is talking about the The Lord met
Moses and sought to kill Moses.
Go ahead.
Then Zipporah took a sharp stone and cut
off the foreskin of her son and cast it
at his feet and said, "Surely a bloody
husband art thou to me." Uh-huh.
So, he let him go and then she said, "A
bloody husband thou art because of the
circumcision."
What do you mean, "A bloody husband thou
art"?
Because of the circumcision, exactly.
Moses, whatever happened, did not
circumcise his sons and the Lord sought
to kill him. Why? Let's go to the
Genesis the 17th chapter. The same
reason why when my sons were born, I had
them circumcised to bring them under the
covenant.
Otherwise, if I don't get circumcised
and my sons don't get circumcised, I'm a
bloody man because my blood going to be
upon me and my children.
Genesis 17,
pick it up at verse 10. We going to get
right to the meat of this. Go ahead.
This is the covenant which you shall
keep between me and you. Start it again,
start it again.
This is my covenant There you go.
which you shall keep between me and you
and thy seed after thee.
Every man child among you shall be
circumcised. Uh-huh. You shall
circumcise the flesh of your foreskin.
And it shall be a token of the covenant
betwixt me and you.
And he that is eight days old shall be
circumcised among you.
Every man child in your generation, he
that is born in the house or bought with
money of any stranger which is not of
thy seed. That money represents the
purchased blood of Jesus Christ. He owns
you. Go ahead.
He that is born in thy house and he that
is bought with thy money
must needs be circumcised. Did Did y'all
see that?
Must needs be circumcised. Go ahead.
And my covenant shall be in your flesh
for an everlasting covenant.
14.
And the uncircumcised man child whose
flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised, that soul shall be cut off
from his people. He have broken my
covenant.
Cut off means to be killed. That's why
the Lord sought to kill Moses because
for some reason he didn't circumcise his
sons and so the reason why Zipporah did
that because Zipporah understood the
covenant of circumcise uh circumcision
being Moses' wife. So she saved her
husband and she saved her sons by
circumcising
uh by circumcising. And she called Moses
your bloody man because you would have
had the bump that blood on on on his
children in the self.
That's all I got to you.
Uh Cornell, that because that's why even
today we must needs be circumcised. The
stranger also, one law for all people.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next.
Next one, Rachel Butler says,
"I have family that use Isaiah 66 verse
23 and 1 Samuel 20 verse 5 as scripture
indicating we should observe the new
moon as a monthly feast but not worship
the actual moon. Any reason not to?
All right. So, they start this question
off about Isaiah 66 and 23 about the new
moon and go ahead brother Tenzin when
you get there read it and the guest
caller will take it from there.
And it shall come to pass that from one
new moon to another and from one sabbath
to another shall all flesh come to
worship before me
said the Lord.
Now, you know
Lord called
his holidays new moons
but the Lord
told you
what to worship and what to keep.
Now, as far as this here Isaiah
66 and 23, that is talking about when
the Lord returned to earth.
And
it have nothing to do with keeping the
new moon.
And this is what people got to
understand. This is strictly the time
when Jesus have returned to the earth.
So, what we going to do is we going to
read a little bit first.
So, that's 66.
Let me see what was he saying? 23?
Yep.
But
we going to find out what time this is.
Let's back up
to the
15th verse.
And start reading.
For behold, the Lord will come with fire
and with his chariots like a whirlwind
to render his anger with fury and his
rebuke with flames of fire.
For by fire and by his sword will the
Lord plead with all flesh.
And the slain of the Lord shall be many.
And they that sanctify themselves and
purify themselves in the garden behind
one tree in the midst, eating swine's
flesh and the abomination of the mouse
shall be consumed together, saith the
Lord.
Now, this is at the coming of the Lord.
He going to kill a whole lot of people.
Including people that eat pig. But go
ahead and read.
For I know their works and their
thoughts, and it shall come to pass that
I will gather all nations and tongues.
And they shall come and see my glory.
Uh-huh. Now, all nations and
He said, all nation and tongue, and they
shall come and see my glory.
From where?
From
Jerusalem. Come and come to Jerusalem
because the Lord is going to be there.
Now, let's look skip down to verse 23
and go ahead.
And it shall come to pass that for one
new moon to another, and for one Sabbath
to another, shall all flesh come to
worship before me, saith the Lord.
>> All of
to worship before me.
And what they going to do when they
come? Read the next verse.
And they shall go forth and look upon
the carcasses of the men that have
transgressed against me.
For their worm shall not die, neither
shall their fire be quenched. And they
shall be
Finish it.
an abhorring to all flesh.
Now, this is talking about when the Lord
This
This is
not speaking
of
worshiping
the new moon or cuz you tell me it is
not worship, but if you keep it and the
Lord didn't
the Lord
feast that the Lord wants you to keep,
he put it
in his feast chapter. But I want to read
something else to you before we go
there.
Go to uh uh
The feast that uh
everybody's going to have to come up and
keep at this time
is the feast of Tabernacle.
So, let's go into uh
uh uh
uh Zechariah 14th chapter.
We're going
read one and then we're going to skip.
Zechariah 14:1 first.
This is during the same time when the
Lord have returned to this earth. He's
going to tell you exactly what you got
to keep and the consequences of not
keeping it.
14:1 reading.
Behold, the day of the Lord cometh.
And thy spoils shall be divided in the
midst of thee.
Now, this is when the Lord come.
Get down to verse three.
And and we're going to read to verse
five. Go ahead.
Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations as when he fought
in the day of battle.
And his feet shall stand in that day
upon the Mount of Olives, which is
before Jerusalem on the east.
And the Mount of Olives shall cleave in
the midst thereof toward the east and
toward the west.
And there shall be a very great valley.
And half of the mountain shall remove
toward the north and half of it toward
the south.
And ye shall flee to the valley of the
mountain, for the valley of the mountain
shall reach unto Azal.
Yea, ye shall flee like as ye fled from
before the earthquake in the days of
Uzziah, king of Judah.
And the Lord my God shall come and all
the saints with thee.
So, now when the Lord come,
his feet going to hit the hit the Mount
of Olives. And and that mountain going
to split just like it was during the
earthquake during the time of Uzziah,
king of Judah.
And he said, "The Lord my God going to
come and all the saints with him." Those
are the people that's going to meet him
in the air.
Now,
and he's going to be on earth. Read
verse nine.
And the Lord shall be king over all the
earth. And in that day shall there be
one Lord
and his name one.
Now, he's going to be king over all the
earth.
And the people that are left that come
against Jerusalem, let's see what feast
they got to keep.
If thou read from 16 [clears throat] to
19.
And it shall come to pass that everyone
that is left of all the nations which
came against Jerusalem shall even go up
from year to year to worship the king,
the Lord of hosts, and to keep the feast
of tabernacles.
To keep the feast of the new moon.
Feast of tabernacles.
Okay, tabernacle.
That's the feast of ingathering.
You find that in 23rd chapter of
Leviticus. But keep reading.
And it shall be that whoso will not come
of all the families of the earth unto
Jerusalem to worship the king, the Lord
of hosts, even upon them shall be no
rain.
And if the family of Egypt go not up and
come not, they have no rain
they have no rain, there shall be the
plague wherewith the Lord will smite the
heathen that come not up to keep the
feast of tabernacles.
This shall be the punishment of Eden of
Egypt and the punishment of all nations
that come not up to keep the feast of
tabernacles.
Now, you notice he didn't say nothing
about the new moon.
Nope.
>> It's because at that time every feast
that the Lord wanted us to keep
represents something.
And when the Lord get back on earth
then the only thing left now is the
ingathering.
Physically, Israel first, but then
spiritually all of the children of God.
Said nothing about the moon.
And I want
And [clears throat] I want to Now, let's
And let's go and
look at this other one they put.
What's that in in where?
1 Samuel 20:5.
Uh-huh, 20:5.
Go on read it.
And David said unto Jonathan, "Behold,
tomorrow is the new moon. And I shall
not fail to sit with the king at meat.
But let me go that I may hide myself in
the fields until the third day at
evening."
That was during the time when Saul was
trying to kill David.
That was nothing but a civil
thing that they was having. Every new
moon they have it. But the whole thing
is, they also have a feast of Purim. We
don't keep that.
The feast of the dedication, we don't
keep that. Cuz none of these have no sa-
salvation
components.
You're just going together on a new moon
and you just eat.
But the feasts that the Lord want you to
keep, he's telling you.
And he didn't name the new moon one
time. Let's go quickly to Leviticus the
23rd chapter because that's just a civil
gathering they're having. Just as the
feast feast of Purim and the and like I
said the dedication.
But let's go and look at what the Lord
said
concerning what he wants you to keep.
Leviticus 23.
And we're going to start reading at
verse one. Leviticus 23:1.
Read it when you get there.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
"Speak unto the children of Israel and
say unto them, concerning the feasts of
the Lord, which ye shall proclaim to be
holy convocation, even these are my
feasts."
Now, look. Don't you think the Lord knew
what he wants you to come together on?
You know what a holy convocation is?
That's holy gathering.
Yeah. are the that the Lord proclaimed
that you should have a holy convocation.
Even these are my feasts.
And what's the first one? Even though we
don't feast on it, but still is under
the heading.
Read the next one.
Six days shall thy work be done, but the
seventh day is a Sabbath of rest, a holy
convocation.
Ye shall do no work therein. It is the
Sabbath of the Lord in all your
dwellings.
Now,
first thing he did was the was the
Sabbath day.
Why he wants you to and you should do
what on that day? Go ahead.
These are the feasts of the Lord, even
holy convocation, which he shall
proclaim in their season.
Now,
whatever feast that the Lord wants you
to keep is right here in the 23rd
chapter of Leviticus.
And you don't see
people feast in the
new moon nowhere in it because this 23rd
chapter, the Lord is telling you to keep
these feasts because they mean
something.
Now, the first one is the weekly
Sabbath.
That Sabbath weekly Sabbath day
represent the 1,000 years that Jesus
going to rule this earth.
Millennial time.
I'm not going to name all of
all of them, but I'm going to just run a
few. Then the next one is the is the
Passover.
That's represent that lamb represent
Jesus.
Like 1 Corinthians 5 and 7 will tell you
that Christ our Passover is sacrificed
for us. That represent the blood of
Jesus. After the Passover, the feast of
unleavened bread.
Leaven means sin. And the Lord wants you
once you come under the blood, you ain't
sin no more for the whole 7 days that
God gave man.
And I can go on and on and on like the
feast of trumpets name. That's the time
when the seven trumpets going to be
blown.
All of the Lord's feasts are written
right here in the 23rd chapter of
Leviticus. If it's not in the 23rd
chapter of Leviticus, you don't have to
keep it because these are the ones say
these are the ones that you must keep
and have a holy convocation. That's all
I have to say.
All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
Next one, Deborah Walter asks for you to
explain 1 John 5:16-18.
1 John 5. Let's go there, brother
Tenzel.
1 John 5 and pick it up at that verse
16. Read it through 18 and the guest
caller I'll take it from there.
If any man see his brother sin a sin
which is not unto death, he shall ask
and he shall give him life for them that
sin unto not unto death.
But there is a sin unto death. I do not
say that he shall pray for it.
But all unrighteousness is sin and there
is a sin not unto death.
But we know that whosoever is born of
God sinneth not.
But he that is begotten of God keepeth
himself and that wicked one toucheth him
not.
Okay, you know that like the sin unto
death,
you know,
uh uh say you shouldn't pray for it.
That's the time when you sin against the
Holy Ghost.
And how do you sin against the Holy
Ghost? By
deliberately distorting or teaching the
word wrong and you know better.
Let's go to Matthew, the fifth chapter.
We're going to read 17 through 19.
Matthew, the fifth chapter.
Uh-huh. 17 through 19.
Think not that I am come to destroy the
law or the prophets.
I am not come to destroy, but to
fulfill.
For verily I say unto you, till heaven
and earth pass,
one jot or one tittle shall in no wise
pass from the law,
till all be fulfilled.
Whosoever therefore shall break one of
these least commandments, and teach men
so, he shall be called the least in the
kingdom of heaven.
Tho- but whosoever shall do and teach
them the same, shall be called great
in the kingdom of heaven.
Now, that's Now, that's the kingdom from
heaven. That's the father's kingdom.
But, the whole thing is, if you uh
He didn't come to change any of them.
But, anybody that come and change
any of them, and teach others to do so,
they're going to be called least in the
kingdom of God. And, you know what's
least in the kingdom of God? The lake of
fire.
That's because if you know better, you
won't keep them, and you teach other
people against it,
then the Lord
There ain't no need of planning for you,
because you because you know better.
Let's go on to Hebrews, the tenth
chapter, and read verse 26 and 27.
For if we sin willfully,
after that we have received the
knowledge of the truth,
there remaineth no more sacrifice for
sin,
but a certain fear looking for of
judgment and fiery indignation,
which shall devour the adversaries.
Do not.
If you sin willfully after you receive
the knowledge of the truth,
there's no more sacrifices for sin. In
other words, Jesus ain't going to die
for you no more and the animals ain't
going to die for you. So, the only thing
you have to do look forward is the lake
of fire. That's the fiery indignation.
That's if you sin willfully after you
have received the knowledge of the
truth. In other words, you know better
and you still breaking God's law.
And then you'll teach against it.
Let's go to the Romans there, first
chapter.
We're going to read verses 18 and 19,
then we're going to skip.
18 and 19.
All right.
Any time
Romans, the first chapter, verses 18 and
19.
For the wrath of God is revealed from
heaven against all ungodliness and
unrighteousness of men who hold the
truth in unrighteousness.
Pay attention what he said. It's
revealed from heaven against all the
unrighteousness of
of unrighteous men that hold the truth
in unrighteousness. They know the truth,
Mhm. but they're teaching it wrong and
they're living it wrong for whatever
reason, but go ahead.
Because that which may be known of God
is manifest in them for God has showed
it unto them.
Uh-huh.
For the invisible things
Go ahead.
What what what verse is that?
I finished 19.
Okay. Read the 19 again and would the
next verse and and that's it. We going
to skip.
For the invisible things of him from the
creation of the world are clearly seen,
being understood by the things that are
made, even his eternal power and
Godhead, so that they are without
excuse.
Now, these are people that know better.
They know the truth. They understand the
word of God, but still they're teaching
against it. So then the Lord give them a
mindset and once you get this mindset,
it is over. Read verse 28.
And even as they did not like to retain
God in their knowledge, God gave them
over to a reprobate mind to do those
things which are not convenient.
Now, once you get that reprobate mind,
it's over with. Let's go to one last
place.
Let's go into 2 Thessalonians, the
second chapter.
And here in 2 Thessalonians, it tell you
about actually talking about the
abomination that worketh desolate the
desolate. In other words, the
uh
the man of sin, which is the pope.
And people that love his teaching
and they go along with his teaching and
this is what the Lord going to do, he
going to give you a reprobate mind
because you love it and you know better.
These are people that know better. Skip
down and read verse 16 and 17.
Now, our Lord Jesus Christ himself and
God even our Father, which have loved us
and has given us
I'm sorry.
2 Thessalonians, second chapter, verse
10 through 12.
I'm sorry.
All right. And with all deceivableness
of unrighteousness in them that perish,
because they received not the love of
the truth that they might be saved.
Well, the man of sin can can
deal with these people. He ain't
deceived them. They don't love the
truth.
So, what's going to happen? Go ahead.
And for this cause, God shall send them
strong delusion that they should believe
a lie.
And what's happened to them? Go ahead.
That they might all be damned
who believed not the truth, but had
pleasure in unrighteousness.
So, now, that's the one that you don't
pray for.
The one that you know they know the
truth, but still they'll get out and
they'll fight against people that know
the truth. And they'll twist the truth
for their own
advantage.
And they know better.
The Lord said, "Don't pray for them."
Pray for the ones that deceived and
don't know.
Because when you get that reprobate
mind, the Lord done gave it to you that
you might be damned. And he said, "Hey,
that is a that is a sin unto death."
I don't need to be praying for nobody
that deliberately distorts the word of
God
with knowledge of it.
I have to say.
Yeah. All right. Want to thank you for
that. And Sister Deborah,
we like to move on to our next question
with a time check. Brother Julius,
can you pick up the read for this next
question, please? Yes, sir.
All right. Thank you for that.
Yes, the time is 8:17.
Uh so, Adam says, "I had a conversation
with someone about forgiveness. They
asked me, can a person be forgiven for
killing themselves? Is there any
scriptures that explains this?"
Well, forgiveness is always a good thing
to have because this whole world is full
of sin and sometimes hey, like the Lord
say, you should
forgive so that you'll be forgiven
yourself. But as far as killing
yourself,
um I haven't read any book on that and
whether not you'll be forgiven for that.
Um and brother Dre had a conversation
about that. We were talking about how,
you know, a lot of the medications
people take it has suicidal tendencies
in it. So it's a lot going on. But let
me tell you why that's not our
responsibility. Let's go to Matthew the
12th chapter. Matthew 12.
And let's pick it up, brother.
At that verse
13. Matthew 12.
And let's pick it up at verse 13 because
this is whose responsibility that falls
on.
Go ahead.
Matthew 12 and 13. Then he said he to
the man, "Stretch forth thine hand." And
he stretched it forth, and it was
restored whole like as the other.
All right. So this is Jesus here that
was healing on the Sabbath day and he
healed this man. Go ahead.
Then the Pharisees went out and held a
council against him how they might
destroy him.
Hm. But when Jesus [clears throat] knew
it, he withdrew himself from this and
great multitudes followed him and he
healed them all.
So he was
on a mission of healing everybody and
cuz he healed this man, then the
Pharisees went out and held council
wanting to destroy him for healing a
brother. Instead of being glad that the
brother was made whole, they go turn
around and get upset about that. Now
skip down to verse 25. Go ahead.
And Jesus knew their thoughts and said
unto them, "Every kingdom divided
against itself is brought to desolation
and every city or a house divided
against itself shall not stand. So, the
beginning of that 25 and Jesus knew
their thoughts. That is who we have to
leave in the hands of someone who might
decide that they
don't want to be here no longer because
they all have to appear before the
judgment seat of Christ. Let's go and
read that, too,
uh brother Julius in that 2 Corinthians
5 and verse 10.
Because if Jesus can read your mind and
then you got to appear before his seat,
then you have to leave all
responsibility
in his hand.
Read that verse 10, brother.
For we must all appear before the
judgment seat of Christ
that every man everyone may receive the
things done in his body according to
that he has done, whether it be good or
bad.
So.
That's all I got on that. We have to
leave that in the hand of the one whose
seat we have to appear before.
Hey, I got Can I add something to that?
Please do.
Let's go to Jeremiah 17 and read verses
9 and 10.
Because like we talked about Cornell,
sometimes people are on medications that
have side effects. It wasn't their
intent to do anything, but some of this
stuff
got them hallucinating and going through
different things, but this is Let's look
at that. Read that scripture, brother.
Jeremiah 17:10.
9 and 10.
I the Lord search the heart.
I try the reins
even to give every man according to his
ways and according to the fruit of his
doings. And the Lord is the one that
searched the heart of man
and knows the reins and he will give
everyone according to their ways and
their doings, but verse 9 says, "The
heart is deceitful above all things and
desperately wicked. Who can know it?"
But it is God that knows it and he will
deal and judge man accordingly. That's
not our call.
That's right.
Absolutely, brother. Not our call at
all. Thank you for that add-on. Is
Julius read the verse 7 for me, please.
Blessed is the man that trusteth in the
Lord and whose hope the Lord is.
Yes. So,
we have to leave that right there
as we continue to move on to our next
question.
Moving on, Valencia asks in Zechariah 11
verses 12 and 13,
and is this the same time as Matthew 27
verse 3 and verse 5?
All right. Zechariah 11 12 through 13
and Matthew 27 3 and 5. Brother Drake,
what you say? Let Let's go read that
Zechariah 11
12 and 13 first and we'll go to the next
one.
And I said it to them, "If you think
good, give me my price. And if not,
forbear." So, they weighed for my price
30 pieces of silver.
And the Lord said unto me, "Cast it unto
the potter, a goodly price that I was
priced at of them." And I took the 30
pieces of silver and cast it to the
potter in the house of the Lord.
Yes, sir.
Now, let's go over and read that Matthew
and
verses 3 and 5.
Matthew 27 verses 3
Then Judas which had betrayed him when
he saw that the he was condemned
repented himself and brought again the
30 pieces of silver to the chief priest
and elders
saying
I have sinned in that I have betrayed
the innocent blood and they said what is
that to us see thou to that
and he cast down the pieces of silver in
the temple and departed and went and
hanged himself
and the chief priest took the silver
pieces and said it is not lawful for to
be put them into the treasury because it
is the price of blood.
And they took counsel and bought with
them the potter's field to bury
strangers in wherefore that field was
called the field of blood until this
day.
Now read verse 9.
Then was fulfilled that which was spoken
again that which was spoken by Jeremiah
the prophet saying and they took the 30
pieces of silver the price of him that
was valued whom they of the children of
Israel did value. So Jeremiah spoke
about it it says but Zachariah wrote
about it and so
is it at the same time? No it's
Zachariah is a prophecy of the time and
this was the fulfillment of it in
Matthew 27. That's all I got.
All right thank you for that brother
hope that answer their question sister
Deborah.
All right so Harold Felder asks in
Genesis 2 verse 9 is Christ as the tree
of life so the tree of life in
Revelation 22 verse 2 on either side of
the river as if there are two trees,
Christ, that gives 12 fruits monthly
with healing leaves, Christ.
So, is that Christ also?
All right, Genesis 2 and 9.
And we talking about some trees here.
Read that verse 9 and guest caller we'll
take it from there.
And out of the ground made the Lord God
to grow every tree that is pleasant to
the sight and good for food.
The tree of life also in the midst of
the garden and the tree of knowledge of
good and evil.
Okay, the first thing, let's let's go
look at something.
Uh and and not and this is not
complicated, but we'll look at it. First
thing, let's go and look
and
show you exactly that these
one is tree of life and the other ones
are not
uh uh uh
a tree that grew out of the ground.
First, let's show you that Jesus is the
tree of life. Let's go to Genesis the
third chapter
and read verses 22 to 24.
And the Lord God said, "Behold, the man
is become as one of us to know good and
evil. And now, lest he put forth his
hand and take also of the tree of life
and eat and live forever."
Go ahead. Yeah, uh verse 24. So, he
drove Go through that
to 24.
Yeah, go through to 24.
Therefore, the Lord God sent him forth
from the garden of Eden to till the
ground from whence he was taken. So, he
drove out the man and he placed at the
east of the garden of Eden, cherubims
and a flaming sword which turned every
way to keep the way of the tree of life.
So now, these cherub angels was not
protecting the the garden of Eden. They
was there around the tree of life. So
that means that the
man couldn't get to them.
So let's go and show you
who is it that dwell between these
cherub angels. Let's go to the 2nd
Kings, the 2nd chapter, and read one
verse. Verse 15.
2nd Kings 2
and verse 15.
2nd Kings 2 and 15.
Read.
>> And when the sons of the prophets, which
were to view at Jericho,
saw him, they said, "The spirit of
Elijah does rest on Elisha." And they
came to meet him and bowed themselves to
the ground before him.
Hold on. Hold on.
Is that 2nd Kings 2 and 15?
Yes, sir.
Mhm.
I don't know
I must wrote that down because it's it's
maybe
Is it 2nd Samuel? 2nd Samuel 6?
Maybe it's maybe 2nd Samuel It what It
tell you right there tell me the Lord
God of Israel that dwell between the
cherubim. Yes, sir. 2nd Samuel 6 uh
I don't know I blew that.
It's
>> 2nd Samuel 6 and 2.
What's it What's it say?
Uh
It says Yes.
And David arose and went with all the
people that were with him from Baale of
Judah to bring up from this the ark of
God, whose name is called by the name of
the Lord of hosts that dwelleth between
the cherubims.
Okay, that lets you know who's dwelling
there. You understand?
Who who was who the cherubim was
uh protecting. They was protecting the
Lord of hosts.
And the Lord of hosts is Jesus, sister.
Uh uh uh
and uh
but I still
wondering why
I had in Second Kings. Look at the But
that that answers it right there. But I
want to look one more time
uh
for this.
Mhm.
Let's see.
Let me see here.
Let me see.
Psalm 99:1 is what you want, guest
caller.
Right. I know I know that's there, but I
want to go to the other one because it
was clear.
It's all clear.
Yeah, I'mma read 99 Psalm 99:1 anyway.
It reads, "The Lord reigneth. Let the
people tremble. He sitteth between the
cherubims. Let the earth be moved."
Okay, they're letting you know that it
is
it's Jesus the one
that is sitting between the chair. He is
the one that they uh uh
that the angels are protecting.
And uh why is he called the tree of
life?
Let's go into St. John the 6th chapter.
Read verse
63 first.
St. John 6
and 63.
It is the spirit that quickeneth. The
flesh profiteth nothing.
The words that I speak unto you, they
are spirit and they are life.
Now,
because the word, that is the tree of
life.
Skip down to verse 66 and read to 68. 66
through 68.
From that time many of his disciples
went back and walked no more with him.
Then said Jesus to the 12, "Will you
also go away?"
Then Simon Peter answered him, "Lord, to
whom shall we go? Thou hast the words of
eternal life."
So now, that's why he is the tree of
life. As we eat in his words, then there
would not have been no death.
But these other
trees, let's go in Now, let's go into
Revelation read about the other.
Revelation 2 and 22.
And then
>> Revelation 22:2.
Yes. Uh-huh.
Revelation 22.
Uh I'll pick it up at uh
verse one. And he showed me a pure river
of water of life, clear as crystal,
proceeding out of the throne of God and
of the lamb.
In the midst of the street of it and on
either side of the river was there the
tree of life, which had which bear 12
manner of fruit and yielded her fruit
every month. And the leaves of the tree
were for the healing of the nations.
Now,
now this
is in the Father's kingdom.
But this is something that was left over
from Jesus' kingdom.
So you know saying, let's go into
Ezekiel first.
And 43rd chapter, we going put Jesus on
the ground here and put him in the
temple. Then we going go further. Let's
go into Ezekiel 43:1 and 2.
Then we're going to skip down and read 4
through 7.
Read it when you
>> Ezekiel 43:1 and 2. Afterwards he
brought me to the gate, even the gate
that look it toward the east. And
behold, the glory of the God of Israel
came from the way of the east, and his
voice was like a noise of many waters,
and the earth shined with his glory.
Okay.
Verse four. And the glory of the Lord
came into the house by the way of the
gate whose prospect is toward the east.
So, the spirit took me up and brought me
into the inner court, and behold, the
glory of the Lord filled the house.
And I heard him speaking unto me out of
the house, and the man stood by me.
And he said unto me,
"Son of man, the place of my throne, and
the place of the soles of my feet, where
I will dwell in the midst of the
children of Israel forever, and my holy
name shall the house of Israel no more
defile, neither they nor their kings by
their whoredom, nor by the carcasses of
their kings in their high places."
Now, he spoke to Ezekiel out of the
house and told him the place of the
my throne and the soles of my feet where
I will dwell in the midst of the
uh uh uh
children of Israel forever. But, he was
saying he spoke to him out of the house.
He was in the temple, right? Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
Now, let's go into Ezekiel the 47th
chapter
and look at what was happening, what's
coming out of that house.
Ezekiel 47
and we're going to start reading at
verse one. Ezekiel 47
and verse one.
Read it.
Afterwards, he brought me again unto the
door of the house, and behold, waters
issued out of from under the threshold
of the house eastward.
For the forefront of the house stood
toward the east, and the waters came
down from under from the right side of
the house at the south side of the
altar.
Then brought he me out of the way of the
gate northward, and led me about the way
without until the garden gate by the way
that looketh eastward. And behold, there
ran out waters on the right side.
And when the man that had brought the
line in his hand went forth eastward, he
measured a thousand cubits, and he
brought me through the waters. The
waters were to the ankles.
Again, he measured a thousand, and
brought me through the waters. The
waters were to the knees.
Again, he measured a thousand, and
brought me through. The waters were to
the loins.
Afterwards, he measured a thousand, and
it was a river that I could not pass
over. For the waters were risen, waters
to swim in.
A river that could not be passed over.
Now, skip down
to verse
seven and read.
Now, when I had returned, behold, at the
bank of the river were very many trees
on the one side and on the other.
Now,
skip down
skip down to verse
12 and read.
And by the river upon the bank thereof,
on this side and on that side, shall
grow all trees for meat, whose leaf
shall not fade, neither shall the fruit
thereof be consumed. It shall bring
forth new fruit according to his months,
because their waters they issued out of
the sanctuary, and the fruit thereof
shall be for meat, and the leaf thereof
for medicine.
So, this is the whole thing. What we saw
in
Revelation 22
is something that's left over from
Jesus' kingdom.
But,
even though they call it tree of life,
it's just a relic, because
there was no more death at that time.
Let me show you what I'm talking about.
Let's go and back Let's go into
Revelation the
chapter and read verse 1 through 4.
Revelation 21:1-4.
And I saw a new heaven and a new earth,
for the first heaven and the first earth
was passed away, and there was no more
sea. And I John saw the holy city, new
Jerusalem, coming down from God out of
heaven, prepared as a bride adorned for
her husband.
And I heard a great voice out of heaven
saying, "Behold, the tabernacle of God
is with men, and he will dwell with
them, and they shall be his people, and
God himself shall be with them and be
their God.
And God shall wipe away all tears from
their eyes, and there shall be no more
death, neither sorrow, nor crying,
nor neither shall there be any more
pain, for the former things are passed
away."
So now, in the Father's kingdom, there
ain't no more death. There ain't no
sickness, no nothing.
So,
and from Revelation 22:2,
that is in the Father's kingdom. These
trees of life are just relics left over
from Jesus' kingdom.
Because the Lord is coming down here,
and 1 Corinthians 15:17 will tell you
that Jesus is going to turn the the
kingdom over to the Father.
It's just like So, just like it was with
the ark of the covenant, you going to
see that in the Father's and in
and in Jesus' kingdom.
So,
these
trees, they're called tree of life,
those are ones that grew out of the
ground.
And during Jesus' time, you didn't need
no doctors. They had 12
They had 12 uh
uh manner fruits, and and each of them
on each side. So, if Jesus is one, these
trees of life is one. But these that are
on each side of the river are more than
one.
So they come out of Jesus' kingdom, but
they're going to be in the Father's
kingdom, but something like a memento or
a relic, just like the ark of the
covenant. Yes, sir. They're different.
They're different.
Like I said in the second chapter, they
created that grew out of the ground.
And also, there are two other trees that
was in the Garden of Eden. So they're
different. The tree of life is Jesus. He
is the God of Israel.
That's all I have to say. Yes, caller,
that that scripture that you quoted in 2
Kings is 2 Kings 19:15.
Oh, okay. Please read it.
Go ahead, read that scripture. Yeah,
19:15.
It reads,
"And Hezekiah prayed before the Lord
and said, 'O Lord God of Israel, which
dwelleth between the cherubims, thou art
the God, even thou alone of all the
kingdoms of the earth. Thou hast made
heaven and earth.'"
Yes, that's what I wanted. That dwelleth
between the cherubims. And when did he
start dwelling between the cherubims? In
the Garden of Eden, when Adam and Eve
sinned.
Yes, sir.
He put him out of the Garden of Eden,
and then put them cherub angels around
him. So every time he looked around in
the throne room, you see the ark of the
covenant. On top of the ark of the
covenant is the mercy seat, and on each
side of the where God set, and on each
side of the mercy seat, what you see?
Cherub angels, don't you? Yep. Yes, sir.
So Jesus is the tree of life. And these
other trees was used during Jesus'
kingdom, where you didn't need no
doctors. If you're hungry, you just
pluck
fruit from the tree of fruit of the
tree, you eat. If you got sick, you eat
the leaves and they would heal you.
But the real tree of men, but that's
uh
life that you could get healed, your
flesh and blood in Jesus kingdom, you
could still die.
But the tree of life that the angels
protecting,
once you eat of that tree, you can't
die. That's all I have to say. And
thanks for the scripture, brother.
>> Yes, sir.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
continue to move on to our next one.
Next one. Brother Anthony asked, "In
Colossians
out the ordinance,
what are these ordinance?"
All right, let's go to that Colossians 2
and let's read that 14.
And let's open it up to the panel.
Colossians 2:14.
Hey, Colossians
Sorry about that.
Colossians 2:14.
It reads,
"Blotting out the handwriting of
ordinances that was against us,
which was contrary to us, and took it
out of the way, nailing it to the
cross." Yeah. And um Brother Jerome, you
said earlier
that was indeed, as we know, that is the
animal sacrifice, correct?
Yeah. Yeah, we tied with the the Hebrews
10.
Yeah.
And
>> Let's go there. Yeah.
>> Hebrews 10. Yeah.
10:1, read it.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hebrews
10:1.
It reads,
"For the law
having a shadow of good things to come,
and not the very image of the things,
can never, with those sacrifices
which they offered year by year
continually, make the comers thereunto
perfect. All right. Now,
down to verse four and then it tell you
why.
For it is not possible that the blood of
bulls and of goats should take away
sins.
Now, keep reading down to verse 10.
Wherefore, when he cometh into the
world, he said, "Sacrifice and offering
thou wouldest not, but a body hast thou
prepared me.
In burnt offerings and sacrifices for
sin, thou hast had no pleasure."
Then said I, "Lo, I come in the volume
of the book, it is written of me to do
thy will, O God."
Above what he said, "Sacrifice and
offerings and burnt offerings and
offerings for sin thou wouldest not,
neither has pleasure therein, which are
offered by the law."
Uh-huh. Then said he,
Go ahead. Then said he, "Lo, I come to
do thy will, O God." He taketh away the
first that he may establish the second.
Go ahead. By the which will we are
sanctified through the offering of the
body of Jesus Christ once for all.
And Jesus was nailed to the cross,
wasn't it?
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
And when he got nailed to it, also, the
ordinance of the animal sacrifice was
nailed there, too. It is not talking
about
law.
That's all I have to say.
Yeah.
When he once he offered himself,
that was the one sacrifice we needed for
the sins.
That's it.
So, the other one couldn't remove the
pain.
That's right. Could not.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question there as we continue to
push forward.
All right. Uh the next question
concerning cooking on a Sabbath day for
a feast day for IOG congregation,
Pentecost.
Can you cook on Saturday before sundown
or do you have to wait until the sun
goes down to start cooking for
Pentecost?
All right. So,
for our viewers out there, Pentecost
falls on Sunday and guest caller, they
want to know, can you begin cooking on
Saturday, the day before Pentecost, or
do you have to wait until the Sabbath is
over to begin your cooking for Pentecost
that'll be on Sunday?
Well, it it depends on
how much time you need to cook.
So, the whole thing is if you can if if
you can uh uh uh uh
if you can do all your cooking on
Pentecost, then do it.
But, if the cooking you got and you
can't get it all done before Pentecost
and you have to start on the Sabbath, as
long as your cooking is for the feast.
But, cuz somebody, you know, like Jesus
told you that the priests
defile
uh uh the Sabbath day
and are blameless.
Uh if you have to cook for the feast on,
then you have to cook. However,
if you don't have to cook and you I
mean, if you have to cook,
if you if you can get it done on
Pentecost and don't have to cook on the
Sabbath day,
then get it done
on Pentecost
and don't cook on the regular Sabbath
day. But, either way it go, you are
carrying God's law. Long as you carrying
out the Lord's law.
That's Matthew 12.
But, read what Matthew 3 that go read
it.
Call the book and verse and read it.
Matthew 12.
>> the 12th chapter. Yes, sir.
Verse 4 and 5.
Matthew 12.
And verse 4 and 5. It reads,
"How he entered into the house of God,
and did eat the showbread, which was not
lawful for him to eat, neither for them
which were with him, but only for the
priest?
Or have you not read in the law, how
that on the Sabbath days the priests in
the temple profane the Sabbath and are
blameless?"
You know how? Why they blameless?
Because you had to have a evening and a
morning oblation, which is the evening
and a morning sacrifice, every day.
That mean they had to kindle a fire
every day to pull that off.
And there's certain services they had to
do on the Sabbath day in the temple.
And the Lord said that they're
blameless. Why? Because they taking care
of his business.
Yes, sir. That's all I have to say.
All right.
>> Anybody else?
Go ahead.
Um
No, I think we pretty much
hit that nail right on the head that you
can cook before the sun go down if you
don't have enough time, and based on
what you cooking. But, if you can do it
after the Sabbath is over and still pull
it off, okay. But if not, we still by
all means must have our feast to the
Lord.
That is a commandment of the Lord.
Yes.
Yeah.
All right. We hope that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Are we walking
now into new territory?
Uh yes, we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, May the 20th, 2026.
My colleague wants you to explain Daniel
verses 20 and 21.
All right, Daniel 10.
Brother Julius, and that verse 20.
Daniel 10:20 and 21.
Then said he, "Knowest thou wherefore I
came unto unto thee?
Now will I return to fight with the
prince of Persia, and when I am going
forth, lo, the prince of Grecia shall
come. But I will show thee that which is
noted in the scripture of truth, and
there is none that holdeth with me in
these things, but Michael your prince."
All right, let's open that up to the
panel to shed a little light on that
verse 20 and 21.
The first thing is
that the
uh uh
angel who gave who was sent
to give a message to Daniel because
Daniel was praying for it. Yeah. Let's
back it up.
Let's back it up. Let's see.
Mhm.
Let's see.
We're going to start this at
I know it begins in at verse one it
begins with
where Daniel had a vision but he didn't
understand the vision.
He started praying. Go pray and start
right there in real skill.
Okay, verse one. In the third year of
Cyrus king of Persia, a thing was
revealed unto Daniel whose name was
called Belteshazzar. And the thing was
true but the time appointed was long and
he understood the thing and had
understanding of the vision.
In those days I Daniel was mourning
three full weeks. I ate no pleasant
bread, neither came flesh nor wine in my
mouth, neither did I anoint myself at
all till three whole weeks were
fulfilled.
Now. And in the fourth and twentieth day
of the first month as I was by the side
of the great river which is Hiddekel,
then I lifted up my eyes and looked and
behold a certain man clothed in
linen whose loins were girded with fine
gold of Uphaz.
Now now what verse was that?
That was the end of verse five.
Skip down to verse 11. Let's see what he
said.
And he said unto me, "O Daniel, a man
greatly beloved, understand the words
that I speak unto thee and stand
upright.
And
for unto thee am I now sent."
And when he had spoken this word unto
me, I stood trembling.
Then said he unto me, "Fear not." I'm
sorry, go ahead.
Go ahead.
Then said he unto me, "Fear not, Daniel,
for from the first day that thou didst
set thine heart to understand and to
chasten thyself before thy God, thy
words were heard and I am come for thy
words.
But the prince of the kingdom of Persia
withstood me one and twenty days but lo,
Michael, one of the chief princes, came
to help me and I remained there with the
king of Persia. Now I am come to make
thee understand what shall befall thy
people in the latter days. For yet the
vision is for many days.
Now. Now this king of Persia, he
withheld
Gabriel, an angel,
for 3 weeks.
So can a flesh and blood man stop an
angel for 3 weeks?
Nope. No.
In fact in fact he had to get Gabriel,
the captain of the Lord's host, not
Gabriel, I mean Michael to come in and
and pull
this prince off Daniel off Gabriel so he
can deliver his message. So who is this
prince of
Persia?
Satan. Satan and them.
That's it.
>> Now.
Now let's skip down to what was it what
what was the other verses? Verse what
what? 21
Yes.
>> Yes.
Let's now start at 20 again.
Then said he, Knowest thou wherefore I
am come unto thee?
Now will I return to fight with the
prince of Persia. And when I am going
forth, lo, the prince of Grecia shall
come.
But I will show thee that which is noted
in the scripture of truth, and there is
none that holdeth with me in these
things, but Michael your prince.
So now who were the So these are the
Gentiles.
Who are the prince of Persia and I go
back to fight with the prince of Persia,
you know, once he done delivered the
message.
And then after meeting
prince of Greek is going to come.
So
you got all these Gentiles. So who
are
their prince? Let's go in the Revelation
the 13th chapter. Yes, sir.
And start reading that verse one.
Revelation 13 and 1.
And I stood upon the sand of the sea,
and I a beast rise up out of the sea
having seven heads and 10 horns. And
upon his horns 10 crowns and upon his
heads the name of blasphemy.
Uh-huh. And the beast which I saw was
like unto a leopard
and his feet were the feet of a bear and
his mouth as the mouth of a lion and the
dragon gave him his power and his seat
and great authority.
And that's the whole Gentile dynasty.
Through the dragon gave him his seat,
his power and great authority. So, who
is the dragon?
Satan the devil.
Satan the devil. Now,
let's go in the Revelation the 12th
chapter and start reading at verse one.
Revelation 12:1
And there appeared a great wonder in
heaven.
A woman clothed with the sun and the
moon under her feet and upon her head a
crown of 12 stars.
And she being with child cried
travailing in birth and pain to be
delivered. And there appeared another
one in heaven and behold a great red
dragon
having seven heads and 10 horns and
seven crowns upon his heads.
Now, who is that great red dragon?
Satan.
Don't he look like the same thing that
the same image we just saw in the
Revelation the 13th chapter?
Yes, sir.
That's because he is the prince of all
of these Gentile nations from Babylon
even to the Roman. Then you got the
Persian and the Greeks.
Hm. He's that prince.
Same thing when you go in
in in Ezekiel, I think, when the Lord
said going
uh that he's uh
he
God said he's wiser than Daniel.
So, this prince of
the prince of Greece, the prince of all
these Gentile nations
uh is Satan the devil. That's all I have
to say.
All right. We hope that answered your
question there. As we continue to move
on, as time is a-ticking, sister.
All right. Uh Bilow says, "Please
explain Ezekiel 1 verses 15 and 16,
especially the wheel within the wheel."
So, that's Ezekiel 1 verses 15 and 16.
Please explain.
All right. Ezekiel 1
15 and 16.
And go right ahead, brother.
Now, as I beheld the living creatures,
behold, one wheel upon the earth by the
living creatures with his four faces.
The appearance of the wheels and their
work was like unto the color of beryl,
and they four had one likeness, and
their appearance and their work was as
it were a wheel in the middle of a
wheel.
All right. So, we know it's just talking
about an angel, but when it comes to the
wheel within a wheel,
I don't think we have a clue. Anybody on
the panel?
Don't have a clue.
All right. Well, we going to leave it
right there, and we going to keep
pushing, sister Deborah, as time is
running out.
All right.
Uh Shanquilla Akujo B. says, "I know an
unbeliever
who doubts prophets because he says
there's no historical trace. For
example, he asks, 'Mary is the mother of
Jesus. Where is her family as of today?
How should I respond?'"
You should tell him he need to read some
history.
All you got to do is go back and read
the Roman history. They'll tell you why
Mary and them was there.
And it is recorded history.
That they was all called back to their
own places
uh uh uh towns and cities to be taxed.
That is in history.
When When Cyrus let go 40,000 Jews to go
back to building the temple
in Jerusalem.
And it's And it's written in the in in
prophecy
in Ezra.
That is history.
One angel killed 185,000
Assyrian soldiers
in one night.
>> One night.
When uh uh uh uh uh
That is written history. This person
don't read history.
All these acts, the Lord said that
the the first
Gentile to rule the whole earth is
Nebuchadnezzar. That's written in
history. After him came the Medo-Persian
Empire. That's written in history. After
then him came the Greek Empire. That's
written in history. After the Greek
Empire came the Roman Empire. That is
written in history. And you can go on
and on.
So, this person that making this
statement
making the statement out of ignorance.
Because if he had know had read some
history and was interested in finding
out about it,
he wouldn't make that statement. That's
all I got to say.
Brother Cordia, could I read that Could
I read that Luke 2?
All right, Luke 2.
Yes, sir. Luke 2.
>> And I'm going to pick it up verse 1 and
to verse to verse 5.
And it came to pass in those days that
there went out a decree from Caesar
Augustus that all the world should be
taxed. And this taxing was first made
when Cyrenius was governor in Syria. And
all went to be taxed, everyone into his
own city.
And Joseph also went up from Galilee out
of the city of Nazareth into Judaea unto
the city of David, which is called
Bethlehem, because he was of the house
and lineage of David to be taxed with
Mary his espoused wife being great with
child.
And that is recorded in history.
Yeah.
So how can someone say there is no
trace?
Yeah, right. We can't We can't trace
ourselves either, but we know we
Israelite by reason of what? By reason
of prophecy, don't we? Yes, sir.
>> Yeah.
That's right. All right. That's all I
got.
>> All right.
Okay. So that was the
question that has ended our evening.
Time check, Sister Deborah. Yes, the
time is 9:01.
9:01. All right. We like to thank
everybody from all around the world who
joined us for this evening and we like
to say if you submitted a question we
didn't get to it, please don't resubmit
it. Sister Deborah take it, put it in
rotation and we will address that
question next Wednesday. So until we all
come together again, we say please be
safe, be blessed, stay prayed up and may
the Lord have mercy on us all as Brother
Julius closes us out.
Our Father which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread. And
forgive us of our debts as we forgive
our debt to us. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver from evil. For
thine is the kingdom and the power and
the glory forever. In Jesus' name we
pray.
Amen.